When that Kaiju showed up and you told me to run away...
怪兽出现后，你叫我逃跑
If you hadn't saved my life then,
那时候要不是你救了我
I would've died today.
我今天早就死了
You really should think about joining the Defense Force.
你真的应该去当防卫队员才对
Thanks, Ichikawa.
市川，谢谢你
You really are a nice guy.
你果然是个好人嘛
I'm going to give the Defense Force another go——
我决定再次立志成为防卫...
Found you.
找到你了
A Kai... A Kai——
怪...
Senpai?
前辈？
"Don't worry!"
「你放心
"Whenever you get scared,
不管什么时候
I'll always be right by your side!"
我都会陪在你身边的」
Hah! You read too much manga, Kafka-kun.
你就像这样
That's so corny!
真肉麻
Don't you dare tell my mom, or your mom, that I said that!
你这家伙，绝对不准跟我妈还有阿姨说！
They'll tell the whole neighborhood...
她们什么都会告诉其他同学的妈妈
Thanks...
谢谢你
Yeah. If we're together, there's nothing to be afraid of.
两个人一起的话，确实就不可怕了
The Kaiju was sighted inside a hospital.
怪兽是在医院里被发现的
Before it can harm anyone...
务必在有人受害之前...
we need to defeat it.
打倒怪兽
EPISODE 2: KAIJU BEATS KAIJU
（第2集：打倒怪兽的怪兽）
A Miniature Kaiju has appeared within Yokohama.
横滨市出现小型怪兽
I repeat. A Miniature Kaiju
重复一次，横滨市出现小型...
This alert sound is so annoying...
这警报吵死了
Fix it, government.
政府不能换个声音吗？
Sho-chan, hurry!
阿翔，快点
Citizens are asked to evacuate to shelters, or lock their doors...
市民请尽速前往避难所，紧闭家中门窗
Turn off the lights.
把灯关掉
Take necessary precaution to keep yourself safe.
请采取必要措施，保护生命安全
Oh! We can show him it's a misunderstanding!
对了，我们来澄清误会
Senpai, give him a smile!
前辈，快微笑
A-A smile?
微笑？
Got it! A smile!
微笑是吧？
Yeah, that's definitely not gonna work.
这绝对行不通吧
I knew it!
我就知道！
Hey, gramps, you okay?
老爷爷，你还好吗？
I'm, like, totally a Kaiju!
这样我真的是怪兽了嘛！
Wh-What was that? An explosion? Is everything okay?
怎么了？爆炸吗？没事吧？
Huh? A Kaiju?
呃，那是怪兽吗？
The Defense Force is probably on their way!
防卫队员快来了
-Let's scram! -Yeah!
-我们快逃吧 -好啊
I'll cause trouble for the hospital if I stay here!
这样下去会造成医院的麻烦
Let's escape out the window!
我们从窗户逃走吧
Should've seen that coming!
你看吧
What's going on with my body?
我这身体到底是怎样啊？
Call the doctors!
快去叫医师！
Let's get going, Senpai!
前辈，我们快逃
H-Hey! Wait!
喂，等等啊！
The Kaiju is fleeing from Yokohama South General Hospital.
怪兽从横滨南综合医院逃走
It's heading for an evacuated area.
正朝向已避难完毕的区域前进
What's going on?
到底是怎么回事？
Senpai's a Kaiju?
前辈变成了怪兽？
Since when? How?
何时开始的？怎么会？
And wait... is he even really a Kaiju?
是说，那真的是怪兽吗？
Um, let me just confirm real quick...
为了保险起见，我想确认一下
It's really you, right, Senpai?
你真的是前辈吧？
I'm not even sure anymore!
我自己也不太清楚
What is that? Some kind of special mode?
这是怎样？是什么模式吗？
That's what I want to know!
我比你更想知道答案！
Look, Ichikawa! I'm eating a bird alive!
市川，你看！我在吃活生生的鸟
Ew! That's really disgusting, Senpai!
好恶！太恶心了，前辈！
Oh! I'm back!
啊，我变回来了
You even revert creepily!
变回来的方式也很恶
Ichikawa, trouble!
市川，不好了
Now what?!
现在又怎么了？
I gotta pee!
我超想尿尿的
Now? Hold it in!
现在？请你憋着
No, I think my body's gonna piss on its own!
不是，想尿的是这个身体啊
I can't hold it in!
我也无可奈何
This isn't good!
我不要啊
I'm a grown man! I don't want to piss on a public street!
身为一个成年人 我才不想在大马路上撒尿啊
Where would you piss from, anyway?
可是你要从哪里尿？
I don't see the right parts...
我好像没看到那个东西啊
Senpai!
前辈！
Now nobody will ever take me as a bride!
我嫁不出去了啦
I'll just die here!
人家不想活了
No, you've got other stuff to worry about, right?
不是，你该担心的不是这个吧
Now let's get going!
好了，走啦
But you know, Ichikawa...
可是市川啊
What happens to me now?
我以后会怎么样啊？ 我还当得上防卫队员吗？
No way! No way! No way!
不可能...
You're what they're defending people from!
你怎么看都是被讨伐的对象
They'll kill you on sight!
你会立刻被扑杀
Yeah, I figured!
也对啦
Huh?
咦？
Which means...
这也就是说...
I'll never be able to join the Defense Force?
我永远无法成为防卫队员了吗？
Damn it...
可恶
Just when I'd decided to try and catch up to her...
我明明决定要再次追上那家伙
How can I do that with this body?
但身体这样，我该怎么办？
Senpai!
前辈
NO ENTRY
（禁止通行）
That's a cordon.
是封锁线
Once we're inside, there'll be nobody around.
进去这里面就不会有人了
Senpai?
前辈？
No, it's coming from underground...
不对，是从地下
What's this?
这是...
Another Kaiju?
另一只怪兽？
Car 2, maintain course.
2号车就这样继续前进
We'll head to the new location.
我们则前往新地点
It's the same type as the one that attacked us.
跟昨天袭击我们的是同一种
You can tell?
你有办法分辨吗？
That means they'll have fewer men to send after you, though.
不过这样一来 负责对付你的队员就会减少
This is our chance to hide.
是藏匿的好机会
Luckily, they already started evacuating when the alert was sent out about you.
幸亏因为前辈的关系 居民都已经去避难了
Let's just pray there'll be no casualties.
我们就祈祷不会出现受害者吧
Mommy! Mommy!
妈妈...
Run... quickly!
你快逃，快点...
Just wait! I'll get you out!
你等我，我马上救你出来
Run!
快跑！
No! You're coming with me!
不要！我要妈妈跟我一起走
Run... please...
快逃，拜托...
Please!
拜托...
No!
不要！
Mommy!
妈妈！
-Mommy! -Please! Please! Please!
-妈妈！ -拜托...拜托
Wow. I'm really strong.
威力真强大
You okay?
你没事吧？
Yeah, of course. Sorry. Sorry.
也对啦，抱歉
Smile!
面带微笑
G-Got it! I'll be gone in a moment! So don't cry!
我知道了，我马上离开，你别哭
-Senpai! -H-Hey...
-前辈 -哦
Mommy! Mommy!
妈妈...
She's just unconscious. She'll be fine.
她只是晕倒而已，没事的
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的吗？ -嗯
Ichikawa, get them out of here.
市川，她们两个就拜托你了
What are you going to do?
你要做什么？
I'm gonna try
我来试试认真地揍一拳
Let's get out of here!
我们离远一点
One, two...
一、二...
Three!
三！
You, uh...
这招...
definitely can't do that to a person.
绝对不能用在人身上
Senpai...
前辈？
It's safe now.
已经没事了
Get your mom to a hospital...
先送你妈妈去医院...
Listen. The Defense Force will be here soon.
你听我说，防卫队马上就会来了
I'll be gone in a second, so don't worry.
我也会离开，所以你放心吧
M-Mr. Kaiju...
怪兽先生
Thank you.
谢谢你
Yeah. If we're together, there's nothing to be afraid of!
两个人一起的话，确实就不可怕了
Yeah, as long as we're together!
嗯，只要我们两个人一起
Let's go!
走吧
That's right...
是啊
I have to go.
我得过去才行
Senpai, I've called for an ambulance.
前辈，我已经请求救援了
Let's get out of here before someone arrives.
趁有人来之前，我们快走吧
Senpai?
前辈？
Ichikawa, I'm not giving up after all.
市川，我还是决定不放弃了
I have to go and stand by her side!
我得去那家伙的身边
What happened here?
这到底是...
What the hell?
这是怎么回事啊？
Tell me about the Kaiju you saw.
麻烦你告诉我，你看到的怪兽
The Kaiju?
怪兽？
Don't worry.
你放心吧
I'll wipe out all the Kaiju.
我会消灭所有怪兽的
Really?
真的吗？
Um, do you promise not to hurt the good Kaiju?
你可以不要打倒 那个善良的怪兽先生吗？
The one who saved my mom.
他救了我妈妈
EYEWITNESS DESCRIPTION
（依目击者证言绘制）
Kaiju No. 8.
怪兽8号
This is the eighth Kaiju that the Defense Force has given a codename.
这是防卫队以代号命名的第八只怪兽
No. 8 remains at large, the Defense Force actively hunting it...
怪兽8号目前仍然行踪不明...
They still haven't found this guy?
还找不到这家伙吗？
Right?
对啊
He's probably dead already.
说不定已经死了
This has gotten way out of hand...
事情闹得很大
It's been three months.
事发至今过了三个月
Senpai became the first Kaiju in history to escape the Defense Force,
前辈成了防卫队成立以来 首度未讨伐成功的事件
and every Defense Force officer in the country is looking for him now.
他也是日本全国的防卫队员 正在追缉的对象
Oh, right. Ichikawa.
对了，市川
You and Kafka got something in the mail.
这是寄来给你跟卡夫卡的
He went to the job site early, so take this to him.
他上早班，已经去现场了，你拿去给他吧
Okay...
好
It's that time already, huh?
已经到了这个时期了啊
Kafka-san used to take the exam every year.
卡夫卡以前每年都会去报考
Every single year.
是一项例行公事
And every year, we'd have to cheer him up.
安慰他落榜的餐会也是
RENO ISHIKAWA
（市川雷诺，第一阶段测验合格...）
Oh, you did it!
哦，好棒
-Nice! -Thanks.
-真有你的 -谢谢
Want me to take Kafka his?
卡夫卡的，需要我拿给他吗？
No, it's fine.
不，没关系
I'll take it.
我拿去给他就好
Looks like he passed, huh?
看来好像是合格咯？
But this'll be his last chance ever, right?
不过，今年是最后一次了吧
I want him to have his one last shot, you know?
真希望他能抓住最后的机会
He's worked so hard for so long...
毕竟他一直都很努力啊
Senpai!
前辈！
You passed the first round of exams!
我通过第一阶段测验了
Seriously?
真假？
Why are you exposing yourself?!
你怎么可以露出原形啊！
Wow, it's a little early to play rough, right?
怎么一大早就这么激烈啊？
Your face! Your face!
你的脸！
Do you know what you look like?
你搞清楚状况好吗？
Crap!
糟糕
I still slip up once in a while...
现在还是会不小心就变成这样
All back to normal!
-这样就行了 -你根本没变回去啊
You were on the news when I was at the office!
我刚才又在办公室看到新闻了
You have to be more careful!
你有点自知之明好吗？
Fine! Fine!
好啦，我知道了
I'm sorry!
对不起嘛
Senpai and I...
我跟前辈...
You're the patients from the room!
是病房里的患者
You okay?
你们没事吧？
Yeah, we just barely survived...
嗯，我们没事
We told everyone we ran away when the Kaiju showed up.
大家以为我们被怪兽吓到而去避难了
I think we fooled everybody, but...
总之，目前似乎还没穿帮
Here. This is yours.
拿去，这是前辈你的
WE ARE PLEASED TO INFORM YOU THAT YOU HAVE PASSED THE FIRST ROUND OF TESTS.
（日比野卡夫卡 第一阶段测验合格...）
Good. Good stuff.
嗯，太好了
I thought you'd be happier.
我以为你会更开心耶
It's always the second round where I fail!
我每次都是在第二阶段失败的
Why do you seem proud of that?
你为什么一脸得意？
So, what will you do?
那你打算怎么办？
Are you really going to take the second round of exams with that body?
你真的要以那个身体 参加第二阶段测验吗？
It'll be fine!
没问题的
Nobody'll know!
我会好好隐藏的
You're not gonna fool anyone!
毫无说服力可言！
The first round is just a written test and some paperwork,
不同于只有书面审查 跟笔试的第一阶段测验
but there'll be officers everywhere at the second.
第二阶段测验时，应该到处都是防卫队员
They'll kill you on sight.
要是穿帮会被立刻扑杀
Even so, I'm taking it.
就算这样，我也要参加
I've spent the past three months trying as hard as I can,
这三个月以来，我做了很多调查
and I can't find a way to turn back.
还是找不到恢复原状的方法
I'm 32 years old. This is my last chance.
对32岁的我来说 这次的测验真的是最后的机会了
JAPAN DEFENSE FORCE RECRUITING NOW
（日本防卫队，招聘队员中）
All right.
我知道了
But even if something happens to you, I'm not going to drop out.
但就算前辈你出了什么事 我也不会停下脚步的
If we're gonna do this, we're doing it as rivals.
既然决定要参加，那我们就是竞争对手了
I can't get the cap off...
瓶盖好紧
I take it back!
我收回刚刚的话
Skip the exam!
你果然还是不行
I'll be fine! I'll be fine!
等等，我没问题的啦
-I'll be good when it's time for the exam! -Transform back!
-测验当天我会好好隐藏的 -你快变回去
Don't abandon me.
别抛弃我嘛
Seriously, no matter what happens, I'm not helping you!
我说真的，不管发生什么事 我都不会救你的
Everybody will be here soon, so get it together!
大家差不多快来了，麻烦你振作点
If he'd passed and I hadn't,
要是只有我不合格
I wouldn't be able to call myself his senpai anymore...
我这前辈的面子要往哪摆啊
Okay. Time for my revenge match.
好，看我怎么雪耻
10 DAYS LATER
（十天后）
DEFENSE FORCE SCREENING EXAM ROUND TWO WEST TOKYO VENUE
（防卫队员第二阶段选拔测验 西东京会场）
MONSTER SWEEPER INC.
（Monster Sweeper）
Wow...
真厉害
So this is the Defense Force's Tachikawa Base...
这里就是防卫队立川基地
I went to Kumagaya Base on a field trip once, but this one's way bigger.
比起我在校外教学参观过的熊谷基地
They share this area with a Self-Defense Force garrison.
因为陆上自卫队的屯驻地 也一并设置在这里
When something happens, both sides work together
遇到状况时，他们就会携手合作
to dispatch troops all over western Tokyo.
派遣队员前往西东京各地
If you transformed here, you'd be dead within seconds.
要是在这里变成怪兽，一瞬间就完蛋了吧
No point in getting scared.
害怕也没用
Let's go!
我们走吧
Hey, old man.
这位大叔
We're a little early, but let's get checked in.
虽然还有点早，我们先去报到吧
I said, old man.
大叔，我在叫你
Senpai?
前辈
Yes, you.
没错，就是你
Pay attention, old man.
你反应有够慢耶，大叔
OLD MAN?
（大叔？）
Me?
我吗？
Is she taking the exam too?
她也是考生吗？
I'm not an old man! I'm still just 32!
我才不是大叔，我才32岁！
That makes you old.
那就是大叔啊
It does?
是吗？
Well, it does.
嗯，是啊
That rust bucket is yours, right?
那辆破车是你的吧？
It's in the way.
挡到我的路了
I can't park my car, so move it.
这样我的车停不了，请你移开
There's tons of open spots!
明明还有很多车位啊
I want to park it there.
我就是想停在这里
My lucky number today is five.
因为我今天的幸运数字是5
Your lucky number?
幸运数字？
What's the deal with this little brat?
这个高傲的臭跩妹是怎样？
Come with me.
你过来一下
This young man is going to teach you a lesson in manners.
让大哥哥教你什么叫做礼貌
Whatever.
算了
I'll move it myself.
我自己来移
What are you going to do?
你突然这样是在干嘛？
That suit...
那套战斗服...
No! The company car!
公司的车！
Examinee number 2016.
准考证号码2016号
Kikoru Shinomiya.
四之宫琪歌露
My hobby is murdering Kaiju.
兴趣是扑杀怪兽
Remember that.
你们给我记好了
Shinomiya? That last name...
四之宫？这个姓氏...
Anyway, old man...
先不说这个了，大叔
Did you know you smell like a Kaiju?
你好像散发着怪兽的味道耶？